NICK Douglas

Senior Web Developer





Πñ

PROFILE

An experienced Senior Web Developer focusing primarily on front end development in Vue.js, React. With over 15 years' front and backend experience I am comfortable in multiple programming languages, web technologies and fast paced environments. Working as a contractor I am expanding my skills and knowledge and gaining great exposure to more complex web apps and websites.

EDUCATION

INTERNET TECHNOLOGY - Bsc (Hons)

Buckinghamshire New University 2003 - 2006

A-LEVELS

St Clement Danes School 1998 - 2000

SKILLS

Vue.js, Vuex, Vue Router, Nuxt, i18n, Storybook, Contentful, React, React Context & Hooks, Redux, Styled Components, HTML, CSS/SCSS, Javascript ES6+, Typescript, Wordpress, Laravel, PHP, MYSQL, Agile

TOOLS

Webpack, Gulp, Grunt, Babel, EsLint, Prettier, Browserify, Autoprefixer, Git, SSH, GitLab, BitBucket

EXPOSURE TO (LEARNING)

Next.js, Vite, Nodejs

EXPERIENCE

SENIOR FRONTEND ENGINEER | FREELANCE

May 2021 - Present (4 extensions)

Vue (Vue 2 & Vue 3), VueX, Vue Router, i18n, Storybook

Working within a smaller team of the frontend team I primarily worked on adding new features to the web app. Our team was tasked with creating a new UI for the factory/location creation process. Working within an Agile environment, the majority of the work for this epic was creating new views and components based on the Figma designs provided. Our team was also put in charge of developing a company component library to be imported into the main project. This was a separate repo so we took the opportunity to use Typescript and Storybook to aid our development process.

SENIOR WEB/VUEJS DEVELOPER I FREELANCE

December 2020 - April 2021

Vue (Vue 1 & Vue 2), VueX, Vue Router, i18n

Working in the small frontend checkout team I worked on bug fix tickets and developing new features for the white labelled checkout section of the website. The frontend checkout is built using Vue and utilising VueX as the state management system. The frontend is connected to a Laravel backend through api routes allowing for a single page application experience.

SENIOR WEB/REACT DEVELOPER | FREELANCE

October 2020 – November 2020

React, React Route, Hooks, Context, Contenful, GraphQL

Using React I helped create the user interface for a charity web app. The app is a football league which inspires fan to take action on climate control.

The UI is linked with headless CMS Contentful and the data is pulled using GraphQL. Routes are created using React Router and the data is stored in React Context.

SENIOR WEB/VUE.JS DEVELOPER | FREELANCE

April 2020 – September 2020

Vue, VueX, Vue Router, Nuxt, Contentful, GraphQL

Using Vue.js and specifically Nuxt.js I worked on and built multiple sites using the headless CMS Contentful. Data is pulled to the site using GraphQL, stored in Vuex state and displayed on the site

Worked on order at table web app that linked with the clients till systems to manage their sales. I created multiple features for these including timeslots, notes and menu choices

Using Contentful I successfully created a dynamic website for one of the clients to allow them to build their site from a selection of components, giving them the ability to create unique web pages as they see fit.

SENIOR WEB/VUE.JS DEVELOPER | FREELANCE

July 2019 - March 2020 (2 extensions)

Vue, VueX, Vue Router, Nuxt

Used Vue.js to build components for websites. An Umbraco JSON API is called which in turns feeds the Vue.js component displaying the required data and giving the necessary functionality to the page.

Built a complete JSON driven Vue.js SPA utilising Vue Router and VueX. Each component is defined inside the JSON and when built, calls the required component using dynamic components.

Built a JSON driven client "brochure site" using Nuxt.js to utilise it's static site generation to ensure the site's is SEO ready as this was a concern of using a Javascript framework. Helped rebuild and refine the Webpack build process for all projects to utilize Vue.js as the primary frontend build tool.

VUE.JS & THREE.JS AR WEB APP PROJECT | FREELANCE (REMOTE)

April 2019 - June 2019

Vue, VueX, Vue Router, Three.js

Used Vue.js with dynamic components to render the required component for each scene, assigned in the scene json file

Using Vuex I was able to store required information such as current scene to help with routing

Vue.js page transitions were used to smoothly move between each scene Used three.js to render 360 videos and add clickable markers to the scene (timestamp) to load information popups that can be saved

LARAVEL & VUE.JS SPA PROJECT | FREELANCE (REMOTE)

February 2019 – April 2019

Vue, VueX, Nuxt, chart.js, Laravel

Used Laravel to handle the database driven/relational data Vue.js with Vue Router was used to serve the necessary pages Used chart.js to render statistic graphs for each employee

CONTRACT WEB DEVELOPER | WICKES

September 2018 – February 2019

HTML, JS, JSON, Handlebars

Converting existing built site to a new HTML/JS/JSON/Handlebars template system using Bootstrap 4.

Created reusable components for use throughout the site

CONTRACT WEB DEVELOPER | RSM AGENCY

August 2018 - September 2018

Vue, VueX, Wordpress

Converted existing Wordpress site from a purchased theme to a custom build Developed a course search using Vue.js with statement management (VUEX)

SENIOR WEB DEVELOPER | IGLOO CREATIVE (PERM)

July 2015 – August 2018

Vue, VueX, Vue Router, Nuxt, Laravel, Wordpress

Lead developer for all web builds, including quoting, planning, managing and developing.

Building Wordpress websites utilising Javascript, jQuery and Vue.js depending on requirements

Built large scale websites using Laravel and vue.js

Applying build tools such as Webpack, Gulp and Babel.